Finding aid for Library (University of Michigan) Clipping file, ca. 1920-1980
Bentley Historical Library
- State of Michigan Clipping File, 1920s-1980s
  - M-Z
    - Michigan
      - Lakes (Box 73)
        (also see 'Great Lakes', 'Water Pollution--Great Lakes' and 'Water Pollution--Michigan')
      - Legislature--Current Bills (Box 73)
      - Legislature--Graft Investigation (Box 73)
      - Mines and Minerals (Box 73)
      - Monuments and Memorials (Box 73)
      - National Guard (Box 73)
      - Population, 2 folders (Box 73)
      - Public Buildings (Box 73)
      - Public Works (Box 73)
      - Upper Peninsula (Box 73)
      - Waterways (Box 73)
        (also see 'Great Lakes', 'Saint Lawrence Seaway', and 'Water Pollution--Michigan')
    - Michigan Academy of Science (Clippings) (Box 73)
    - Michigan Academy of Science (Pamphlets) (Box 73)
    - Michigan Interscholastic Press Association (Box 74)
    - Michigan Schoolmasters' Club (Box 74)
    - Michigan State University [General] (Clippings), 3 folders (Box 74)
    - Michigan State University [General] (Pamphlets) (Box 74)
    - Michigan State University--Medical School (Box 74)
    - Michigan Technological University (Box 74)
    - Milliken, William G. (Box 74)
    - Moody, Blair (Box 74)
    - Murphy, Frank (Box 74)
    - National Defense--Civilian--Michigan (Box 74)
    - Newspapers--Michigan (Box 74)
    - Oakland University (Box 74)
    - Old Age--Michigan (Box 74)
    - Olivet College (Box 74)
    - Osborn, Chase S. (Box 74)
    - Parole and Probation--Michigan (Box 74)
    - PBB (Box 74)
    - Pittsfield Village (Box 74)
    - Portraits--Michigan (Box 74)
    - Potter, Charles E. (Box 74)
    - Poverty--Michigan (Box 74)
    - Prisons and Prisoners--Michigan
      - General, 2 folders (Box 74)
      - Jackson, 3 folders (Box 74)
      - Special (Box 74)
    - Public Health--Michigan (Box 75)
    - Public Welfare--Michigan (Box 75)
    - Regional Planning--Michigan (Box 75)
    - Republican Party--Michigan (Box 75)
    - Romney, George, 7 folders (Box 75)
    - Saint Lawrence Seaway (Clippings) (Box 75)
    - Saint Lawrence Seaway (Pamphlets) (Box 75)
    - Sallade, George Wahr (Box 75)
    - Seals (Box 75)
    - Sigler, Kim (Box 75)
    - Social Security--Michigan (Box 75)
    - Staebler, Neil (Box 75)
    - Stratford National Theatre of Canada (Box 75)
    - Taxation--Michigan (Box 75)
    - Taxation--Michigan--Veterans (Box 75)
    - Tunnels--Detroit (Box 75)
    - Universities and Colleges
      - Academic Costume, Insignia, etc. (Box 75)
      - Michigan--A-Z (Clippings) (Box 75)
        (Look under individual school names for Albion College, Eastern Michigan University, Michigan State University, Michigan Technological University, Oakland University, Olivet College, Washtenaw County Community College, and Wayne State University)
      - Michigan--General (Clippings), 2 folders (Box 75)
      - Michigan--[General] (Pamphlets) (Box 75)
    - University Microfilms Inc. (Box 75)
    - Veterans--Michigan (Box 76)
      (also see 'Taxation--Michigan--Veterans')
    - Veterans Organizations (Box 76)
    - Vivian, Weston E. (Box 76)
    - Washtenaw County
      - Education (Box 76)
      - History (Box 76)
      - Medicine, 2 folders (Box 76)
      - Police (Box 76)
      - Politics and Government, 2 folders (Box 76)
      - Social Services (Box 76)
      - Social Services--Aid for Children (Box 76)
      - Social Services--CEO (Box 76)
        (Washtenaw County Citizens' Committee for Economic Opportunity)
      - Social Services--Welfare (Box 76)
    - Washtenaw County Community College (Box 76)
    - Washtenaw Historical Society (Box 76)
    - Water Pollution--Great Lakes (Box 76)
    - Water Pollution--Michigan, 2 folders (Box 76)
    - Wayne State University (Box 77)
    - Williams, G. Mennen, 3 folders (Box 77)
    - Women, Bibliography (Box 77)
    - Ypsilanti (Box 77)
    - Ypsilanti--Greek Theater (Box 77)
The researcher can also find similar materials, with a larger emphasis on pamphlets and printed ephemera as well as more recent content, in the vertical files maintained by the Bentley Historical Library. Each of the vertical files has a separate finding aid and folder listing available.
Biographical Vertical File (DB)
Alphabetical University of Michigan Vertical File (Fimu)
Vertical File
The State. Michigan History. Government, Description (EA - EE)
Michigan Organizations (FA -FZ)
Michigan Newspapers (NB)
Michigan Imprints [items published in Michigan] (OA)
For Michigan politics and public administration, see the clipping and pamphlet files maintained by the Bureau of Government Library at the University of Michigan from 1935 to 1980. There is a separate finding aid under University of Michigan Bureau of Government Library (87106 Bimu C 448 2).
Additionally researchers can check for printed material and publications from University of Michigan groups and units by looking to see if the group or unit has a publications finding aid, a publications series in a manuscript/records finding aid, or a file in the university publications drop boxes (an alphabetically arranged collection of miscellaneous and uncatalogued publications produced by university entities).